# IOAKEIM HADJIMPALASIS

ioakeim.h@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ioakeim-h in

357 - 99250369 (



https://ioakeim-h.github.io/

# >> DATA SCIENCE | MACHINE LEARNING

#### MOTIVATION

I am passionate about solving business problems using Data Science & Machine Learning. I systematically & creatively use my skillset to add tangible value to the team, the business, and the end-user. I have been trained in research methods and gained professional experience from reputable organisations in the UK and Cyprus. I am constantly learning, and always looking to improve.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python (Base, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn), SQL, R, SPSS

Machine Learning: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, KNN, k-means, PCA, Association Rule Learning, Causal Impact Analysis

Hypothesis Tests: Within & Between Subjects Designs (t-test, ANOVA & variants)

Data Cleaning & EDA: Data Accuracy, Missing Data, Outliers, Categorical Data (Cardinality Reduction, Resampling, Encoding), Feature Scaling & Selection

Other: Web Scraping, Github, MS Office

### SOFT SKILLS

Communication: Provided live sessions for master's students who requested support with statistics. Explained theoretical and practical topics and shaped the learning experience according to individual needs and capabilities.

Leadership: Organised and delivered coaching session for undergraduate students. Created a supportive and autonomous learning environment. Ensured a variety of tasks for individuals at different levels.

Persuasion: Presented evidence-based arguments in front of an audience in a debate with a fellow student at the University of Essex. Explored ways to "sell" my ideas and focused on the limitations of the opposition.

Research: Designed the methodological procedure of a study, recruited and tested participants in a laboratory, analysed the data collected, discussed findings and successfully developed a scientific report for university.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## IT Advisor, Digital Innovation Team - KPMG (CY)

FEB 2022 - PRESENT

- Used Python to prepare and clean data of an international ship management company that looked to optimise resources. Worked on a dataset with more than 800 000 rows where I used regular expressions to locate errors, cardinality reduction and encoding techniques
- Basic data manipulation in Python to enable analysis for a major financial services company.

# Professional Placement, Leadership Team - Office for National Statistics (UK)

JUN 2021 - SEP 2021

• Used R to analyse Census data from 2011 and 2021. Decided on suitable variables, cleaned these and produced descriptives that helped senior leadership diagnose potential issues.



ioakeim.h@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ioakeim-h in

357 - 99250369 (

https://ioakeim-h.github.io/

# https://ioakeim-h.g

# EDUCATION

#### **MSc (Psychology)**

2020 - 2021 - Cardiff University, UK

>> DATA SCIENCE | MACHINE LEARNING

#### **BSc (Sports and Exercise Science)**

2017 - 2020 - University of Essex, UK

## **CertHE (Sports Science and Coaching)**

2016 - 2017 - University of Bolton, UK

#### COURSES & CERTS

#### **DATA SCIENCE INFINITY**

Actionable Learnings: Extracting & manipulating data using SQL. Application of statistical concepts such as hypothesis tests for measuring the effect of AB Tests. Utilising Github for version control, and collaboration. Using Python for data analysis, manipulation & visualisation. Applying data preparation steps for ML including missing values, categorical variable encoding, outliers, feature scaling, feature selection & model validation. Applying Machine Learning algorithms for regression, classification, clustering, association rule learning, and causal impact analysis for measuring the impact of an event over time. Machine Learning pipelines to streamline the ML pre-processing & modelling phase. Deployment of a ML pipeline onto a live website using Flask & Heroku. Turning business problems into Data Science solutions.

#### CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python, Harvard University (edX)

Syllabus: Functions, Variables | Conditionals | Loops | Exceptions | Libraries | Unit Tests | File I/O | Regular Expressions | Object-Oriented Programming | Et Cetera

#### R programming, Jons Hopkins University (Coursera)

Syllabus: Data Types & Objects | Reading & Writing Data | Control Structures | Functions | Scoping Rules | Dates & Times | Loops & Loop Functions

#### The Data Scientist's Toolbox, Jons Hopkins University (Coursera)

Syllabus: Data Science Fundamentals | R & RStudio | Version Control & Github | Rmarkdown, Scientific Thinking & Big Data

#### **Discovering Personality**, Dr Jordan B. Peterson (online)

Syllabus: Introduction to Personality Psychology | The Five Factor Model: An Empirical Approach to Personality | Extraversion: Enthusiasm and Assertiveness | Neuroticism: Volatility and Withdrawal | Agreeableness: Compassion and Politeness | Men and Women: Personality Differences | Conscientiousness: Industriousness and Orderliness | Openness to Experience: Intellect and Openness.